<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Design on The Practice of Information Architecture</title>
    <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Design on The Practice of Information Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Colour Contrast</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/colour_contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/colour_contrast/</guid>
      <description>Designing With Colour # Colour Contrast: # Our visual system combines the signals from retinal cone cells to produce three colour-opponent channels:
red-green, yellow-blue, and black-white. The colours that people can distinguish easiest are those that cause a strong signal (positive or negative). Not surprisingly, those colours are red, green, yellow, blue, black, and white. All other colour cause signals on more than one colour channel, causing our visual system to struggle to distinguish between them as quickly as the listed six colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readability</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/readability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/readability/</guid>
      <description>Readability of Content: # Unfamiliar/Uncommon Vocabulary: # Use vocabulary that readers are familiar with and don’t disrupt the flow of freaking - stick to words that are easy to understand.
Difficult Script/Typefaces: # Fonts with minimal spacing or difficult shapes make it difficult to recognize - stick to simple, easy-to-read fonts.
Tiny Fonts: # Fonts that are too small can cause the readers’ visual system to be unable to read the content - stick to a font size that is appropriate for all audiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good vs bad design</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/bad_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/visual_design/bad_examples/</guid>
      <description>Good Vs. Bad Design: # Design can be evaluated by clarity, consistency, and understanding the user&amp;rsquo;s goals. Designers should stay consistent with their content, ensuring that the information is legible and stays within the topic category.
Avoid Ambiguity: # Use clear information displays and test your design to ensure that all users understand the display in the same way. Where ambiguity is avoidable, use standards or conventions to resolve it, and stay uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
