<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organizing Information on The Practice of Information Architecture</title>
    <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organizing Information on The Practice of Information Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Information Blocks</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/information_blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/information_blocks/</guid>
      <description>Information Blocks # Information Blocks are an alternative way to present and analyze information instead of a paragraph. They are used for small bits of sections of information grouped together with a specific purpose, such as instructions, warnings, steps, or short documents like procedure, policy, and process documentation.
Characteristics of an information block Short sentences (2-9) Short paragraphs Single or limited topic Always has a label Can be a diagram Constructed via 4 Principles Chunking, Relevance, Consistency, Labeling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chunking</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/chunking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/chunking/</guid>
      <description> #Chunking # Breaking information into smaller “chunks” so it’s easier to understand and digest. By creating visual entry points, it makes it easier for the user to navigate the document and scan for the information they are looking for or get the key highlights
if=&amp;#34;you looked here first&amp;#34; then=&amp;#34;code blocks are an effective example of information chunking&amp;#34; else=&amp;#34;...?&amp;#34; profit=[true] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labels</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/labels/</guid>
      <description>Labels # Labels act as shortcuts to communicate information efficiently. They are used for guiding readers or users while navigating the site by scanning for the relevant label.
If someone wants to find contact information for a business they’ll look for a contact label, if they want to navigate back to the home page they will look for the home button or text, a restaurant webpage will normally have a menu label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Size &amp; Content</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/size_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/size_content/</guid>
      <description>Headings # The following HTML &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;—&amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; elements represent six levels of section headings. &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; is the highest section level while &amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; is the lowest.
H1 # H2 # H3 # H4 # H5 # H6 # Paragraph # Xerum, quo qui aut unt expliquam qui dolut labo. Aque venitatiusda cum, voluptionse latur sitiae dolessi aut parist aut dollo enim qui voluptate ma dolestendit peritin re plis aut quas inctum laceat est volestemque commosa as cus endigna tectur, offic to cor sequas etum rerum idem sintibus eiur?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Map/Template</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/information_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/information_map/</guid>
      <description>Information Maps &amp;amp; Templates # An information map is a way of structuring information on a page using two or more information block types. Each block is short, spaced out, and chunked into different sections that contain a single topic with no irrelevant information.
Information mapping allows you to transform a wall of text into clear information with road posts (labels) people can skim and look at to digest the information quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tables</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/organizing_information/tables/</guid>
      <description> Tables # Name Age Bob 27 Alice 23 Italics Bold Code italics bold code one two three four five 1111 22222 3333 44444 5555 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
