<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on The Practice of Information Architecture</title>
    <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/categories/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on The Practice of Information Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/categories/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Information Architecture</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Information architecture # In a digital world where we are overloaded with all the information we could want at our fingertips, it can be overwhelming to try and sort through it all. Information architecture is the solution to that problem.
Similar to IT, people often don’t think about information architecture unless it’s done badly. Good information architecture means a user is easily able to navigate a website, app, or skim a document to find important information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of Information Design</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/</guid>
      <description>Information Architecture (IA) # We are a group of information designers who collaborated to produce a set of materials with the intention of contributing to the greater design collective through a showcase of skill, knowledge and understanding from within the field.
The Book &amp;amp; The Digital Companion # The result is a collection of information architecture resources.
While comprehensive enough for a fellow designer, the book serves as an introduction to the topic of information architecture for the brave and curious alike.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
