<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information types on The Practice of Information Architecture</title>
    <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/categories/information-types/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information types on The Practice of Information Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/categories/information-types/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Information types</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/information_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/information_types/</guid>
      <description>Information Types: # The type of information can be distinguished by process, structure concept, principle, fact, and classification. Information types are not necessarily limited to these six categories, as they can be defined as organization systems, labelling systems, navigation systems, and search systems. These, however, refer more so to information structures, rather than systems.
For all intent and purposes, the six main categories are as listed and defined below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/information_types/good_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/information_types/good_examples/</guid>
      <description>Examples of Information Types: # When compiling information, there are specific examples of information types that a designer can follow, for instance:
Site Mapping: # Refers to the process of creating a visual representation of a website’s structure, layout, and content.
Tap + to explore the interactive map of this site The Practice of Information Design
Information Architecture
Glossary
Information types
Examples
Good vs bad design
Organizing Information
Information Blocks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good vs bad design</title>
      <link>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/information_types/bad_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-of-information.netlify.app/information_types/bad_examples/</guid>
      <description>Good Vs. Bad Design: # Design can be evaluated by clarity, consistency, and understanding the user&amp;rsquo;s goals. Designers should stay consistent with their content, ensuring that the information is legible and stays within the topic category.
Avoid Ambiguity: # Use clear information displays and test your design to ensure that all users understand the display in the same way. Where ambiguity is avoidable, use standards or conventions to resolve it, and stay uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
